Guide to the South African Apartheid Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, 1961-1991 (inclusive), 1990-1991 (bulk); Accession 1995-M-101
  - Non-parliamentary/opposition/pressure groups
    - Worker's Organisation for Socialist Action (WOSA), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - South African institutes and foundations
    - Centre for Development Studies, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Centre for Intergroup Studies (CIS), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Institute for a Democratic Alternative for South Africa (IDASA), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 72 - 73)
    - Institute for Contextual Theology, 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Institute for the Study of Public Policy, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Malta Trust, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - South Africa Foundation, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - South African Institute of International Affairs, 1961, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - South African Institute of Race Relations
      - 1973, 1978, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 79)
      - 1990 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Southern Africa Labour and Development Research Unit (SALDRU), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - American anti-apartheid pressure groups
    - Africa Fund, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - African-American Labor Center/AFL-CIO, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - American Federation of Labor/AFL-CIO, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Episcopal Churchpeople for a Free Southern Africa, 1987, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - National Anti-Imperialist Movement in Solidarity with African Liberation (NAIMSAL), [1983?] (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Revolutionary Communist Party (RCP), 1981 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Washington Office on Africa, [1991?] (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - International pressure groups
    - African European Institute, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Anti-Apartheid Movement (AAM), London, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Anti-Apartheids Beweging Nederland (AABN), 1991 (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - Australian Anti-Apartheid Movement, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Bishop Ambrose Reeves Trust (BART), London, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - British Defence and Aid Fund for Southern Africa, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - Canon Collins Educational Trust for Southern Africa, London, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Christian Action, London, [1964] (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Christian Aid, London, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Committee on South African War Resistance (COSAWR), London, 1983, 1984, undated (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - Commonwealth Heads of Government Meetings; Harare Communique, London, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - End Loans to South Africa (ELTSA), London, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - International Campaign against Banking on Apartheid (ICABA), London, 1988-1991 (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - International Defence and Aid Fund for Southern Africa, London, [1970?], 1991 (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - International Freedom Foundation, London, Washington, D.C., 1988, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Irish Anti-Apartheid Movement, Dublin, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Isivivane, Berlin, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Labour Research Department (LRD), London, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Oxfam, Oxford, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - Research on Education in South Africa (RESA), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - Scottish Committee Anti-Apartheid Movement, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Shipping Reseach Bureau, Amsterdam, 1985-1987, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - South Scan, London, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - United Nations, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 112)
- Additional Material, late 1970s; Accession 1997-M-082
  - After the Collapse of Apartheid: an Inside View of Race Politics in South Africa, by Jordan K. Ngubane [photocopy of typescript], [late 1970s] (Box 1)
- Additional Material, 1982-1986, undated (inclusive); Accession 1997-M-104
  - South African government, South African Defence Force (SADF), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Non-parliamentary/opposition/pressure groups
    - Black Sash, 1982-1985, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Campaign Against Sexual Abuse" (CASA), undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Conscientious Objector Support Group (COSG), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - The Centre for Intergroup Studies [paper on conscientious objection], 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Detainees' Parents Support Committee (DPSC)/ Detainees' Support Committee (DESCOM), undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "End Conscription Campaign" (ECC), undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Let South Africa Speak" [initiative of South African business and professional people; includes cover letter and manifesto], undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Moderate Student Movement (MSM), 1985, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - National Association of South African Students (NUSAS), [1985?], undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - South African Outlook [an independent journal dealing with ecumenical and racial issues], 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - South African Students' Press Union (SASPU), [1985?] (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Standing Advisory Committee on Company Law (SAC), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Transvaal Rural Action Committee (TRAC), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - United Democratic Front (UDF), [1985?], undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - University of Cape Town (UCT), 1985, 1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - The Upstairs Theatre Company (Steve Biko: The Inquest; includes biographic information], [1985?] (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified [pertaining to compulsory fingerprinting], [1982?] (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Additional Material, Accession 1997-M-153
  - New Unity Movement [printed material consisting of bulletins, journals, newsletters, press releases, reports, and speeches]
    - 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Additional Material, Accession 1998-M-092
  See also: Accession 1998-M-092 Folder 39
  See also: Accession 1998-M-092 Folder 33
  See also: Accession 1998-M-092 Folder 51
  See also: Accession 1998-M-092 Folder 163
  See also: Accession 1998-M-092 Folder 224
  See also: Accession 1998-M-092 Folder 221
  This accession consists primarily of printed material collected by the Washington Office on Africa. Items are listed alphabetically by names of organization, personal name, or by title of publication. Subject files and photographs are included at the end of the listing.
  - Africa, 1976, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Africa Committee, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Africa Fund
    - General, 1980-1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Southern Africa Perspectives, 1980-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "Unlock Apartheid's Jails" [protest campaign], 1987, 1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Africa Information Centre, New Zealand [includes Pan Africa ], 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Africa News, 1975-1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Africa Publications Trust (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Africa Report, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - African Music and Drama Association, 1963 [ca. 1972] (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - African National Congress (ANC)
    See also: Accession 1998-M-092 Folder 65
    See also: Accession 1998-M-092 Folder 22
    See also: Accession 1998-M-092 Folder 197
    - General, 1980-1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Amandla, [1982?] (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Biographies of various members, [1989], [1991] (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Dawn, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Films, promotional flyers, 1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - The Freedom Charter, 1975-1986 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - International Conference: "Peoples of the World Against Apartheid for a Democratic South Africa", 1987 December 1-4 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Mandela, Nelson, 1978, 1979, 1983 1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
      See also: Accession 1998-M-092 Folder 22 See also: Accession 1998-M-092 Folder 197
    - Mandela, Winnie, 1970, 1975, 1976, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Mission to the United States, 1990, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - National Union of South African Students (NUSAS), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - The Nelson Mandela National Reception Committee, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Observer Mission to the United Nations, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Press releases and statements, 1979, 1986, 1987, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Publicity and Information Bureau, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Solomon Mahlangu Freedom College (SOMAFCO), 1985, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - South African Political Prisoners' Day, Washington, D.C., 1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Tambo, Oliver, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Voice of Women, 1986, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Albert Einstein Institution, Cambridge, MA [ Nonviolent Sanctions ], 1990, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - All-Africa Press Service (APS), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - All-Africa Convention and Non-European Unity Movement, 1963, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - American Broadcasting Company (ABC), New York [ Nightline transcripts], 1985 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - American Committee on Africa (ACOA)
    - General
      - 1965, 1970, 1971, 1975-1981 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - 1982-1987, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - ACOA Action News, 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - U.S. Student Anti-Apartheid Movement Newsletter, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - American Cyanamid, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), 1982, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1977, 1987, [1988?] (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Anti-Apartheid Bewegung in Osterreich, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Anti-Apartheid Movement
    - London, [1979], 1983, 1984, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Netherlands, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Norway, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Association of West European Parliamentarians for Action Against Apartheid (AWEPPA), 1985-1990 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Azania News, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Baragwanath Hospital, Johannesburg, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Biko, Steve [inquest re the death of], 1977 December 6 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Black Consciousness Movement (BCM)
    See also: Accession 1998-M-092 Folder 49
    - General [includes Solidarity ], 1974-1982, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Biko Steve, 1972, 1976-1978, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Black Peoples' Convention (BPC), 1972-1978, undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Black Sash, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Bophuthatswana [Bop-Tenth Anniversary Edition], 1987 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Botha, P. W., 1981, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Botha, Tozamile, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - British Defense and Aid Fund for South Africa, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - The Campaign Against Investment in South Africa (CAISA), undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Campaign Against Racial Exploitation (CARE), Australia, 1976, 1986-1988, 1990, 1991, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Canada, Government of, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Canadian Labour Congress (CLC) [ Labour's World ], 1986 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Cape of Good Hope Foundation [ Cape of Good Hope News ], 1990 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Catholic Institute of International Relations (CIIR), 1985, 1986, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Center for Constitutional Rights, New York, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Center for Development Policy, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS), 1969, 1981, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Center for Third World Organizing [ Third Force ], 1983 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), 1975-1977, undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Citizens for Participation in Political Action (CPPAX), 1997 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Coalition of American Public Employees (CAPE), undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Coalition on Southern Africa (COSA), 1987 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - The Coke Campaign [ Corporate Watch ], 1987 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Commonwealth Committee of Foreign Ministers of Southern Africa, undated (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Community for Creative Non-Violence, undated (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Conference for a Democratic Future, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Conference on Public Investment and South Africa, New York, 1981 June 12-13 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Congress of South African Trade Unions (COSATU), 1986, undated (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - The Conservative Caucus, 1985, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Constitutional Rights Foundation, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Council of Unions of South Africa (CUSA), 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Covert Action, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Defense Marketing Services, Inc. (DMS) [intelligence report], 1976 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - De Kieffer and Associates, undated (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - De Klerk, F. W., [1990?] (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Democratic Party, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Detainees' Parents Support Committee (DPSC), 1985-1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Detainees' Support Committee (DESCOM)--Detainees' Parents Support Committee (DPSC), 1985 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Durban Students Union, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Educators Against Apartheid, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Embassy of South Africa, 1989, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - End Conscription Campaign, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - End Loans to South Africa (ELTSA), 1986, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Episcopal Churchpeople for a Free Southern Africa (ECSA), 1986 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Federale 1940-1990 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Federation of Transvaal Women, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Focus '63, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Freedom at Issue, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Freedom Fighter, undated (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - "From Pentacost to Soweto", 1989, undated (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Hart: The New Zealand Anti-Apartheid Movement (NZAAM) [includes Amandla and Hart News ], 1982, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - The Heritage Foundation, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Holland Committee on Southern Africa [ Sport and Apartheid ], 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - Human Awareness Programme, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - "The Indian Community in the Transvaal" [exhibition], 1991 September (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Information Centre on South Africa, Amsterdam, 1987, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - Information Service of South Africa, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Institute for a Democratic Alternative for South Africa, undated (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - Institute for Food and Development Policy, [1990?] (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Institute for Strategic Studies [Symposium on National Security], 1977 March 31-April 1 (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - International Bulletin, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - International Campaign Against Banking on Apartheid (ICABA), 1989 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - International Defense and Aid Fund for Southern Africa (IDAF), 1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - International Freedom Foundation (IFF), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - International Labor Office (ILO), 1981, 1985, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - International League for Human Rights, [1985] (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union (ILWU), 1986 (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - International Monetary Fund, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - International Possibilities Unlimited, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - Insolera Sydafrika Kommitten (ISAK/ Afrikagrupperna, 1987, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - Japan Anti-Apartheid Committee, Tokyo, 1987, undated (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - King, Martin Luther, 1963, undated (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - Labour and Economic Research Project (LERP), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - Labour Party, 1972, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Lawyers Against Apartheid, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - Lawyers Committee for Civil Rights Under Law, 1985, 1988, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - Library of Congress [Congressional Research Service], 1985 (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - The Lincoln Trust, undated (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - The MacNeil-Lehrer Report, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - The Martin Luther King, Jr. Center For Nonviolent Social Change, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - The McAlvany Intelligence Advisory (MIA), 1985 (Box 5, Folder 131)
  - Michigan State University, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 132)
  - The Minority Rights Group (MRG), undated (Box 5, Folder 133)
  - Namibia, Government of National unity, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 134)
  - National Anti-Apartheid Committee/ Council of Wellington, New Zealand, 1979, undated (Box 5, Folder 135)
  - National Council of Churches of Christ, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 136)
  - National Namibia/Southern Africa Concerns, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 137)
  - National Party, undated (Box 5, Folder 138)
  - National Student Anti-Apartheid Strategy Conference, 1981 October 3-4 (Box 5, Folder 139)
  - National Union of Metalworkers of South Africa (NUMSA), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 140)
  - National Union of South African Students (NUMSA), 1972, 1977-1978, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 141)
  - New Africa News, Australia, 1986-1989 (Box 5, Folder 142)
  - North Atlantic Assembly, 1972 November 19-24, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 143)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), 1970, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 144)
  - North South Roundtable, 1986 March (Box 5, Folder 145)
  - Northeast Southern Africa Solidarity Network (NESCAN), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 146)
  - Office on World Community of Lutheran World Ministries, [1984?] (Box 5, Folder 147)
  - Omkeer, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 148)
  - Pan Africanist Congress (PAC)
    - General, 1972, 1977-1978, 1981, 1982-1985, n.d (Box 5, Folder 149 - 150)
    - The History of the Pan Africanist Congress of South Africa [interviews], 1968-1973
      - 1968 May- Sep (Box 5, Folder 151)
      - 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 152 - 157)
    - Pro Veritate, 1975 May (Box 6, Folder 158)
    - Religious News Service (RNS), TX, 1990 June 13 (Box 6, Folder 159)
    - Republic of South Africa
      See also: Accession 1998-M-092 Folder 55
      - Customs and Excise, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 160)
      - Department of the Prime Minister [Government Gazette], 1987 April 19 (Box 6, Folder 161)
      - Identification Bill, [1986] (Box 6, Folder 162)
      - Parliament [speeches by P. W. Botha], 1985, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 163)
  - Revolution in South Africa Action Committee, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 164)
  - The Revolutionary Worker, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 165)
  - "Riv Apartheids Fanglese!" [petition], undated (Box 6, Folder 166)
  - Royal United Service Institute for Defense Studies, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 167)
  - Shell International Petroleum Company, Ltd., 1987 October (Box 6, Folder 168)
  - Shipping Research Bureau, 1985-1987, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 169)
  - Solidarity News Service, [1984?] (Box 6, Folder 170)
  - South Africa Institute of Race Relations (SAIRR), 1977 (Box 6, Folder 171)
  - South African Black Alliance, 1987 August (Box 6, Folder 172)
  - South African Communist Party (SACP), [1986?] (Box 6, Folder 173)
  - South African Congress of Trade Unions (SACTU), 1977, 1985-1986, undated (Box 6, Folder 174)
  - South African Council of Churches (SACC), 1988 (Box 6, Folder 175)
  - South African Education Program, 1980 October- 1982 June (Box 6, Folder 176)
  - South African Military Refugee Aid Fund (SAMRAF), 1979, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 177)
  - South African Non-Racial Open Committee for Olympic Sports (SAN-ROC), 1964 January (Box 6, Folder 178)
  - South African Student Apartheid Bulletins, [1977?] (Box 7, Folder 179)
  - South African Students Organization (SASO), 1971, 1975, undated (Box 7, Folder 180)
  - Southern Africa Dossier, 1982, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 181)
  - Southern Africa Liberation Centre, Australia, 1979-1981 (Box 7, Folder 182)
  - Southern Africa News Agency (SANA), 1977 April 29 (Box 7, Folder 183)
  - Southern Africa Support Campaign (SASCA), undated (Box 7, Folder 184)
  - Southern Africa Support Project (SASP), 1980, 1983, 1984, undated (Box 7, Folder 185)
  - Southern African Development Research Association (SADRA), 1983 (Box 7, Folder 186)
  - Southern African Research and Documentation Centre (SARDC), 1989 (Box 7, Folder 187)
  - Soweto Students Representative Council, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 188)
  - Summit of the Frontline Heads of State and Government, Angola, 1986 April 8 (Box 7, Folder 189)
  - Support Committee for African Liberation Day (SCALD), 1982 (Box 7, Folder 190)
  - The Trademarks Project, Canada, undated (Box 7, Folder 191)
  - TransAfrica Forum, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 192)
  - Transformation Resource Centre, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 193)
  - Umsebenzi, Australia, undated (Box 7, Folder 194)
  - United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America (UAM), 1988 (Box 7, Folder 195)
  - United Democratic Front (UDF), 1983, 1985, undated (Box 7, Folder 196)
  - United Nations
    - General, 1962, 1978, 1981, 1982, 1987, 1988, undated (Box 7, Folder 197)
    - Permanent Mission of South Africa to the United Nations, 1977, 1982, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 198)
  - United States, government of
    - Anti-Apartheid Act, 1986, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 199)
    - Assistant Secretary of State for African Affairs, 1981, 1982, undated (Box 7, Folder 200)
    - Congress
      - Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe (CSCE), 1991 (Box 7, Folder 201)
      - Congressional Black Caucus, 1975, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 202)
      - Congressmen, 1968-1988
        - Anderson-Conyers (Box 7, Folder 203)
        - Crockett-Diggs (Box 7, Folder 204)
        - Dixon-Javitz (Box 8, Folder 205)
        - Kennedy-Tsongas (Box 8, Folder 206)
      - H. Con. Res. 122 (Box 8, Folder 207)
    - Department of Justice, 1979, 1983, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 208)
    - Department of State, 1962, 1963, 1972-1976, 1981, undated (Box 8, Folder 209)
    - Foreign policy, 1975, 1978, 1980, 1989, undated (Box 8, Folder 210)
    - Legislative action, 1979-1981, 1984, undated (Box 8, Folder 211)
    - Presidency, 1968, 1980, undated (Box 8, Folder 212)
  - United States-South Africa Leader Exchange Program (USSALEP), 1983, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 213)
  - The Unity Movement of South Africa, 1965, 1976-1978 (Box 8, Folder 214)
  - University of Cape Town, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 215)
  - University of North Dakota, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 216)
  - University of the Witwatersrand, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 217)
  - University of Zimbabwe, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 218)
  - University of Zululand, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 219)
  - USA for Africa, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 220)
  - The Washington Office on Africa
    - General, 1985, 1989, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 221)
    - Educational Fund, 1985-1988, undated (Box 8, Folder 222)
  - Washington Report on Africa, 1985, 1986, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 223)
  - Woods, Donald, 1978, undated (Box 8, Folder 224)
  - World Campaign Against Military and Nuclear Collaboration with South Africa, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 225)
  - World Council of Churches (WCC), 1988 (Box 8, Folder 226)
  - World Peace Council (WPC), 1982, 1984, 1988, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 227)
  - Subject files
    - General information, [1966], 1967, [1980-1981], [1991] (Box 8, Folder 228)
    - Business and economics, 1976, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 229)
    - Communism, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 230)
    - Conscientious objectors, 1978, 1981, 1988, undated (Box 9, Folder 231)
    - Fragments [miscellaneous], 1972, 1978, [1985?], 1987, [1991?], undated (Box 9, Folder 232)
    - Human rights violations testimonies, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 233)
    - Israel and apartheid
      - 1982-1986 (Box 9, Folder 234)
      - 1987-1990 (Box 9, Folder 235)
    - Media reporting, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 236)
    - Newspaper articles and newsletters, 1976, 1979, 1983, 1987-1991, undated (Box 9, Folder 237)
    - Popular magazines, 1980, 1987, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 238)
    - Portugal
      - 1968-1972 (Box 9, Folder 239)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 240)
      - n.d. (Box 9, Folder 241)
    - Prisoners/detainees
      - 1974-1975, [1977] (Box 10, Folder 242)
      - 1985-1988 (Box 10, Folder 243)
    - South African Military, 1977-1979, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 244)